Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, 1859-2002 (bulk 1916-1960)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES
  - Massachusetts Mothers' Health Council
    - Meetings
      - Luncheon and dinner 1939-41 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Office inventories and insurance policies 1939-44 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Programs
      - Community Projects 1939, undated (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - Program director reports 1939-40 (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - School for Prospective Fathers 1940, undated (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - 25th Anniversary of the Margaret Sanger Birth Control Clinic 1941 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Publicity
      - Articles, typescripts, and manuscripts 1939-42, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Exhibits 1940-42, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Mailings
        - Form letters 1939-44 (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
        - Listsundated (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - Test mailing plan
          - Correspondence 1941 (Box 37, Folder 6)
          - Membership campaign 1941, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Moviesundated (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Newspapers (correspondence) 1940-43, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Open House Benefit 1941 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Press releases 1939-43 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Public opinion polls
        - Benson & Benson
          - Correspondence 1940 (Box 37, Folder 12)
          - Survey 1940 (Box 37, Folder 13)
        - Gallup 1940 (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Public relations committee 1939 (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Publications
        - Drawings for publicationsundated (Box 37, Folder 16)
        - Family Guardian 1939-42 (Box 37, Folder 17)
        - Newsletter to coordinating committees 1940 (Box 37, Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous 1939-43, undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - Quiz sessions 1940 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Radio 1940-45 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Sanger tour of Massachusetts
        - Memos, programs, and invitations 1935 (Box 38, Folder 3)
        - Press releases, itinerary, correspondence, and publication 1940 (Box 38, Folder 4)
        - Holyoke Affair 1940-41, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Speakers
        - Speakers Bureau 1939-40 (Box 38, Folder 6)
        - Physicians 1938-42 (Box 38, Folder 7)
        - Sermons 1942 (Box 38, Folder 8)
        - Speeches 1938-43 (Box 38, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous 1938-43 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Staff
      - Attendance sheets 1941-44 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Field Director reports 1939-40, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Meetings 1939-42 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Officers and directors 1940-44 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Unemployment compensation 1939-42, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Clergymen's Advisory Committee
    - Campaign for signatures 1947, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Clippings 1948-59, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Denominations
      - Baptist 1945-56, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Christian Science 1948, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Churches of Christ 1931-48, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Congregational 1937-57, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Episcopal 1942-56, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Humanist Fellowship 1950 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Jewish 1945-60, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Lutheran 1946-58, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Methodist 1938-57, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Presbyterian 1946-59, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Roman Catholic 1931-48, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Society of Friends 1938-48, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - Unitarian, 1944-60, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - Universalist 1947-54 (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous 1946-55 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Lists of clergy 1942-57, undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Meetings 1946-56 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Moral Law Committee
      - Meetings 1948, undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - Statements 1947-51, undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Notes and miscellaneous items 1932-52, undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Officers
      - Chairman
        - Eliot, Frederick May, 1945-52 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Fallon, George A. 1952-53, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
        - Knight, Walter K. 1953-56, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Secretary (Napoleon W. Lovely) 1957, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Organizations
      - Massachusetts Council of Church Women 1951 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Massachusetts Council of Churches
        - Correspondence, minutes, memos, and reports 1945-56, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - Publications
          - Christian Outlook 1947-48, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 7)
          - Miscellaneous 1946-54, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous 1943-49, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Publicity
      - Form letters 1944-56, undated (Box 40, Folder 10-11)
      - "Pope and Birth Control" by W. P. Everts 1936 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - Radio 1947-48, undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - Referendum 1947-48, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous 1947-48 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Sermons and statements 1929-59, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Men's Committee for Medical Rights
    - Acceptances 1941 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising
      - Correspondence 1941 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous 1946 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Lists 1940-41, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda, reports, and press releases 1941, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Williams, Sydney (Chairman)
      - Correspondence 1940-41, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Notes 1940-41, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Physicians Committee for the Defense of Medical Rights
    - Correspondence
      - Doctors against 1939-41, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Doctors for 1939-41, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Ellis, Laurence (secretary) 1939-40 (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
      - Form letters 1941-42 (Box 41, Folder 12-13)
      - Miscellaneous 1939-43 (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
    - Executive Committee
      - Members 1939-40 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Minutes 1939-42 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - List of physicians 1939-42, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Massachusetts Medical Society 1935-39 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Organizational plans 1938-40, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Printed material 1932-45, undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Publicity
      - Press releases 1939-41 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Statements 1938-40, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Questionnaire and analysis 1936-47, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Speeches 1940, undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts
    - Annual Reports 1945, 1949, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors
      - Annual meetings 1945-65 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Notes, announcements, statements, and correspondence 1945-60 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Clinics
      - Fertility reports 1950-56 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Hospital clinics 1953-66 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Personnel training 1960-67, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Committees
      - Educators' Advisory
        - Correspondence and notes 1939-53, undated (Box 43, Folder 7-8)
        - Essay contest
          - Announcement and flyers 1951-53 (Box 43, Folder 9)
          - Announcement lists 1951-52, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
          - Correspondence 1951-57 (Box 43, Folder 11)
          - Entrants and inquiries 1951-53, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
          - Essays 1951-53 (Box 43, Folder 13-14)
          - Evaluation committee 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - Judges
            - Acceptances 1951-52, undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
            - Regrets 1951-52 (Box 44, Folder 3)
          - Prize winners 1952-53 (Box 44, Folder 4)
          - Prize winning essay 1952 (Box 44, Folder 5)
          - Prizes 1951-52 (Box 44, Folder 6)
          - Publicity
            - Clippings 1952 (Box 44, Folder 7)
            - Press releases 1951-53 (Box 44, Folder 8)
        - Form letters 1946-48 (Box 44, Folder 9)
        - Mailing lists 1942-46 (Box 44, Folder 10)
        - National Citizen's Commission for the Public Schools 1949 (Box 44, Folder 11)
        - Reports and organization 1946-52 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Executive
        - Minutes 1943-67 (Box 44, Folder 13-19)
        - Questionnaire 1948 (Box 44, Folder 20)
      - Field 1947 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Finance, [see Financial materials] (Box 45)
      - Legal Advisory
        - Correspondence on sterilization and abortion 1961-68 (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Memos, minutes, notes, and lists 1950-58 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Medical Advisory
        - Family Planning Service 1957, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - Form letters 1958-61, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - Lists 1947, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Nominating 1949-54 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Organization 1954-56, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Physician's Committee for Planned Parenthood
        - Correspondence
          - Faxon, Nathaniel (chairman) 1947-55 (Box 45, Folder 9)
          - Response to mailings (membership and contributions) 1951-52 (Box 45, Folder 10)
        - Doctors' charts 1952 (Box 45, Folder 11)
        - Executive committee 1948 (Box 45, Folder 12)
        - Form letters 1947-56 (Box 45, Folder 13)
        - Membership 1946-52, undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
        - Publications: "A Word From Your Doctor" 1948-50 (Box 45, Folder 15)
        - Referendum 1948 (Box 45, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous lists, newsletters, and notes 1948-52 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Personnelundated (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Policy
        - Legal 1957-58 (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Recommendations 1957-58 (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Reports, memos, and notes 1949-60, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Social agencies 1958 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Post Election 1948 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Program, [see also Programs]
        - Correspondence 1955 (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - Minutes 1949-55 (Box 46, Folder 8)
        - Reports 1946-67 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Referendum 1948 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Social Workers 1942-53, undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Special Advisory 1968 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Subcommittee to Study Wording of New Legislation 1951, undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Young married women 1946 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Constitution and by-laws 1945-59 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - Form letters
        - Checklists 1948-51, undated (Box 46, Folder 16)
        - Drafts 1946-51, undated (Box 46, Folder 17)
        - New mothers and fathers 1949-59, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
        - New voters 1953 (Box 46, Folder 19)
        - Organizations and staff 1945-66 (Box 46, Folder 20-22)
        - Social workers 1950-53 (Box 46, Folder 23)
        - Volunteers and local communities 1949-53 (Box 46, Folder 24)
        - Miscellaneous 1947-78, undated (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - Religious response
        - Catholic and Jewish 1937-56, undated (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
        - Miscellaneous clergy 1961-67 (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor 1952 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials
      - Accounts, ledgers, and expenses 1948-53 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Appeals: form letters and printed materials 1945-78, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Campaigns
        - Memoranda 1946 (Box 47, Folder 8)
        - Plans, reports, appeals, and correspondence 1941-55, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Donor lists 1946-59 (Box 47, Folder 10-11)
      - Finance Committee
        - Budget and treasurer's reports 1945-62 (Box 47, Folder 12)
        - Correspondence 1937-45, undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
        - Fundraising, tax liability, and miscellaneous memos 1953 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Foundations and grantsundated (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Tax and insurance information 1945-58 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - History and program 1953, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Meetings, Annual 1946-93 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Programs, [See also Committees - Program]
      - Analysis 1968 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Course on Population Problems 1945-46 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Educational 1953-54 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Family Counseling Service 1955-60 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Premarital counseling n. d. (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Visiting
        - Correspondence
          - Arnold, Maud 1953-60 (Box 48, Folder 7-8)
          - De Grange, Chase 1956-60 (Box 48, Folder 9)
          - Morain, Mary 1953-59 (Box 48, Folder 10)
          - Miscellaneous 1953-60 (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
        - Newsletters, form letters, and miscellaneous materials 1952-60, undated (Box 48, Folder 13-14)
        - Personnel 1954-59 (Box 48, Folder 15)
        - Reports 1952-61, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Rhode Island Maternal Health Association reports 1960 (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Springfield field visit 1956 (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Telephone 1965, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Visitor's Notebookundated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Publicity
      - Boston Redevelopment Authority 1962-63, [see also SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES] (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Comic book 1957-59, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Cuts and layoutsundated (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Editorials 1952 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Exhibit controversy (Massachusetts League for Nursing)
        - Correspondence 1962-63 (Box 49, Folder 10)
        - Publications and minutes 1961-63 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Fertility party 1952-53 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Literature requests 1950-51 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Notes 1946-53, undated (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Organization relations
        - Church women's organizations 1945-53 (Box 49, Folder 15)
        - Women's clubs 1945-52, undated (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Photographs
        - Family Planning Association of India, 6th International Conference 1959 (Box 49, Folder 17)
        - Personnel and speakers 1936-53, undated (Box 49, Folder 18)
        - Publicity and miscellaneous 1935-40, undated (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Press releases 1946-62, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-6)
      - Printing costs
        - Birth Control and the Massachusetts Law 1953-59 (Box 50, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous 1956 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Public opinion polls
        - Benson and Benson 1947, [see also Massachusetts Mothers' Health Council - Publicity- Public opinion polls] (Box 50, Folder 9)
        - Questionnaires on 1954 referendum 1950-54 (Box 50, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous 1938-56 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Publications
        - The Advocate 1991-92 (Box 50, Folder 12)
        - Brochure drafts 1958 (Box 50, Folder 13)
        - Correspondence 1945-48 (Box 50, Folder 14)
        - Family Guardian 1939-40 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Pamphlets and brochures 1940-59, undated (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
        - PPLM Hours 1950-59, [see also Committees - Executive] (Box 51, Folder 4-7)
        - PPLM Reports 1974-80 (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Planned Parenthood News 1947-70 (Box 51, Folder 9)
        - Reprints 1947-48 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Radio
        - Broadcast schedules 1947-53, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence 1946-60, undated (Box 52, Folder 2-3)
        - Federal Communications Commission 1947-49 (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - "Health is Wealth" 1955, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
        - Scripts 1948-53, undated (Box 52, Folder 6-7)
        - Speeches 1942-60, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
        - Ted Jones dismissal 1947-49, undated (Box 52, Folder 9)
        - WBZ Editorial 1956-66 (Box 52, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous 1939-49 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Rama Rau, Lady: speaking engagement 1953 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Slogan contest 1950 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Speakers Bureau
        - Correspondence
          - Clergy and church women's groups 1953-57, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
          - Potential speakers 1948-53 (Box 53, Folder 4)
          - Women's organizations 1945-56 (Box 53, Folder 5)
        - Forms 1953-54, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
        - Press releases 1954-58, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
        - Reports to Executive Committee 1946-48 (Box 53, Folder 8)
        - Schedules 1953-60, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
        - Speaker's kit 1947-53, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
        - Speaking engagements: correspondence and reports 1946-53 (Box 53, Folder 11-14)
        - Speakers Manual 1985 (Box 53a)
        - Speaking engagements: correspondence and reports 1954-61 (Box 54, Folder 1-6)
        - Speeches 1946-53 (Box 54, Folder 7)
        - Suggestions and outlines for speeches 1947-53, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Western Massachusetts 1963-66, undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Staff
      - Executive Director 1959-66 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Executive Secretary 1955 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Field representative (Thelma Daniels) 1964-65 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Lists 1947-66 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - President 1946-47 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Social workers 1945-53 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
      - State director 1944-46 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Volunteers 1947-57 (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
- SERIES IV. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS
  - Affiliated organizations
    - American Birth Control League
      - Annual and miscellaneous meetings 1937-41 (Box 55, Folder 11-13)
      - Board of Directors 1932-38 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - By-Laws and statement of goals 1934, undated (Box 55, Folder 15)
      - Clinics
        - Clinical Research Bureau 1925 (Box 56, Folder 1)
        - Directory of Clinics 1937 (Box 56, Folder 2)
        - Minimum standards for clinics 1935, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
        - National Clinic Courier 1935-38 (Box 56, Folder 4)
        - "New Clinic Loan Fund" 1935 (Box 56, Folder 5)
        - Reports 1933-38, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Conferences
        - Conference on Appeal to Supreme Court 1938 (Box 56, Folder 7)
        - International Neo-Malthusian and Birth Control Conference (6th) 1925 (Box 56, Folder 8)
        - National Birth Control Conference 1929 (Box 56, Folder 9)
        - Regional Conference on Birth Control 1935 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Joint Committee of ABCL and Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau 1938 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Publicity
        - Clippings 1937-38 (Box 56, Folder 12)
        - Press releases 1935-37, undated (Box 56, Folder 13)
        - Publications
          - Birth Control Review subscriptions 1932-33, undated (Box 56, Folder 14)
          - News Bulletin distribution 1935, undated (Box 56, Folder 15)
          - Reprints distributed by ABCL 1923-35, undated (Box 56, Folder 16)
          - Miscellaneous 1927-38, undated (Box 56, Folder 17)
        - Publicity contest 1935 (Box 56, Folder 18)
      - Reports 1927-58 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Birth Control Federation of America/Planned Parenthood Federation of America, [see also Planned Parenthood-World Population]
      - Annual meetings and reports 1940-45 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
      - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings 1939-46 (Box 57, Folder 4-11)
      - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings 1947-61 (Box 58, Folder 1-10)
      - By-laws and constitutions 1940-65 (Box 59, Folder 1-5)
      - Clinics 1937-45 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Committees
        - Biological Research 1955-60 (Box 59, Folder 7)
        - Field 1948-62 (Box 60, Folder 1-5)
        - Long Range Planning
          - Memoranda 1949 (Box 60, Folder 6)
          - Programs 1949-52 (Box 60, Folder 7)
          - Reports 1949-54 (Box 60, Folder 8)
          - Staff studies 1953 (Box 60, Folder 9)
          - Study questions 1953 (Box 60, Folder 10)
          - Miscellaneous 1949-66 (Box 60, Folder 11-13)
        - Medical
          - Correspondence 1945-57 (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
          - Membership 1948-62 (Box 61, Folder 4)
          - Memoranda 1945-61 (Box 61, Folder 5)
          - Minutes 1952-61 (Box 61, Folder 6-8)
          - Reports 1939-63 (Box 61, Folder 9-10)
        - Operational Levels 1957 (Box 61, Folder 11)
        - Public Progress 1939-43, undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
        - Social Research
          - Correspondence 1954-59 (Box 62, Folder 1)
          - Memoranda 1958-60 (Box 62, Folder 2)
          - Minutes 1957-61 (Box 62, Folder 3)
          - Reports
            - "Contraception and the Poor" 1959-61 (Box 62, Folder 4)
            - "Studies of Attitudes Toward Family Planning and Contraception in the Working Class" 1959 (Box 62, Folder 5)
            - Future Directions of Social Research in the PPFA 1961 (Box 62, Folder 6)
            - Summary of professional staff meeting 1961 (Box 62, Folder 7)
            - Social Science and Social Action (symposium) 1962 (Box 62, Folder 8)
            - Miscellaneous reports and studies 1958-62 (Box 62, Folder 9-11)
      - Conferences
        - Conference on Social Research 1958 (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - Physiological Mechanisms Concerned with Conception 1959-64 (Box 63, Folder 2)
        - Race Building in a Democracy 1940 (Box 63, Folder 3)
        - Southern Conference on Tomorrow's Children 1939 (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - Strengthening Our Population for National Defense 1941 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, PPLM/PPFA
        - 1939-41 (Box 63, Folder 6-15)
        - 1942-60 (Box 64, Folder 1-17)
      - Financial materials
        - Budgets 1952 (Box 65, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence 1947-51 (Box 65, Folder 2-3)
        - Dues from PPLM to PPFA 1943-62 (Box 65, Folder 4-6)
        - Fees 1939-46 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
        - Finance reports 1943-64 (Box 65, Folder 9-10)
      - Medical Program 1941 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Meetings 1956-63 (Box 66, Folder 2-5)
      - National Clergy Advisory Committee 1943-51, undated (Box 66, Folder 6-9)
      - Negro service
        - Correspondence 1941-52 (Box 66, Folder 10)
        - Reports and printed materials 1940-49, undated (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Organization
        - "Cresp, McCormack & Paget Report: A proposed information system" 1966-67 (Box 66, Folder 12)
        - Policies, procedures, and organization chart 1940, 1962-66, undated (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Public relations
        - Correspondence and memoranda 1939-63 (Box 67, Folder 1-12)
        - Press releases 1957-67, undated (Box 67, Folder 13)
        - "Program of Public Information for the BCFA" 1939 (Box 67, Folder 14)
        - Publications
          - Lists 1940-41, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 15)
          - Planned Parenthood News and News Exchange, 1940-67 (Box 67, Folder 16)
          - Miscellaneous 1938-67, undated (Box 67, Folder 17-18)
        - Radio scripts 1947-49, undated (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
        - Speakers and speeches 1952-54, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Relationship between program and new contraceptives (PPFA staff study 2) 1953 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - South End Report 1968 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Staff 1939 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - State Leagues 1943-46 (Box 68, Folder 7-9)
      - United Community Services Application 1957 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Planned Parenthood League of Connecticut, [see also SERIES VI. LEGISLATIVE FILES - Connecticut and SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES and SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES]
      - Correspondence
        - 1938-57 (Box 68, Folder 11-17)
        - 1958-65 (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
      - Meetings, minutes, and reports 1944-59 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Publicity
        - Correspondence 1946-48 (Box 69, Folder 4)
        - Newsletters 1944-61 (Box 69, Folder 5)
        - Pamphlets and miscellaneous printed materials 1947-73, undated (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Planned Parenthood of Western Massachusetts 1967-68, undated (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Planned Parenthood - World Population:
      - Family Planning Service Legislation 1966-68 (Box 69, Folder 8-9)
      - National Conference on Family Planning 1966 (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Northeastern Region Workshop 1967 (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous 1968 (Box 69, Folder 12)